Ruby on Rails Developer

Dmitrii Rozilainen

Espoo, Finland

dmitry.rozi@gmail.com

Fi: +358 46 615 1014, Ru: +7 905 253 06 44

Professional summary

A web-developer with 4 years experience in software development and more than 2 years experience with Ruby on Rails framework (Ruby 2.5.3 and Rails 5.2), PostgreSQL, Sidekiq, RabbitMQ in eCommerce marketing automation services. I am well-versed in Model-View-Controller (MVC) architecture using Rails as a back end API, Vue.js as a front end framework.

Experience

04/2020 - Present

Back-end Developer at REES46 (www.rees46.com)

Startup provides marketing automation services for eCommerce, based in Saint Petersburg, Russia

- Developing third party service integrations (send customers reviews to other eCommerce platform, sync client's subscription permissions from public Turkish service IYS, connections to specific SMS gates)
- Developing back end for platform visual editors (email template editor, crm flow editor)
- Developing back end for customer's bonus loyalty program
- Developing new customer's reports
- Developing RSpec tests
- Refactoring current code base
- Bug fixing
- Working in a team with the lead developer, frontend-developer and QA-engineer

10/2018 - 04/2020

Technical Expert at Digital Design (www.digdes.com)

Custom software development company based in Saint Petersburg, Russia

- Developing prototypes of CMS software using no-code framework editors, HTML, CSS, SQL
- Calculating design and implementation costs of Content Management System software (CMS Docsvision)
- Interaction with clients, support and gathering requirements for development

04/2008 - 09/2018

Technical department engineer at Visec (www.visec.ru), Saint-Petersburg, Russia

Company offers complex security solutions for banks, airports, hotels, warehouses.

- Configuring IP CCTV servers (Windows- and Linux-based) with high-load storage systems, network commutators (level 2, 3)
- Configuring face recognition software modules, license plate recognition software modules
- Technical support for customers
- Training other engineers to design and maintain security systems, IP CCTV system

Core programming skills: Other skills:

- Ruby 2.5
- Ruby on Rails 5,6
- Sinatra
- TDD, EDD

- Frontend: HTML, CSS, Rails Slim templates with AJAX, Bootstrap
- DBMS: PostgreSQL, Redis, Memcached, ClickHouse
- Sidekiq, RabbitMQ
- Testing framework RSpec
- Git, Linux CLI, Docker

Education

2001-2007 ITMO University, Saint-Petersburg, Russia

Information Security Specialist with a major in Integrated Computer System Security

2017 - 2018 www.goodprogrammer.ru, www.rubyschool.ru

Ruby on Rails Development full course

2018 www.udemy.com courses

Web-development, SQL, PostgreSQL

About myself

I'm adept of continuous learning and my curiosity is not limited by developing only tech skills.

In my free time I like traveling with my family, cooking, snowboarding, climbing and hanging out at music festivals.